<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Ryan Roe]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Ryan Roe]]></description>
        <link>http://ryanroe.io/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 06:44:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://ryanroe.io/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 06:44:03 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Thread: Network+]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Thread: Network+</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2350cd8f-e14e-4783-8691-47c90d1c6c33.png">,<p>Image: An Internet Mapping from The Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers’ The Opte Project</p>,<p>This thread is my collection of notes on the various topics involved with a CompTIA Network+ Certification.</p>,<p>May 8, 2018</p>,<p>Ryan Roe</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://ryanroe.io/thread-network/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">a2ca3462-e557-4bf8-b86a-1564d202db7b</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 23:27:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Analyzing E-Commerce Business Strategies & Developing and Testing a Mobile Application E-Commerce Business Model]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Analyzing E-Commerce Business Strategies &amp; Developing and Testing a Mobile Application E-Commerce Business Model</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/8e38ea99-4485-48d1-a724-0d84da237fe0.png">,<p>A 27 page research paper analyzing e-commerce business strategies followed by global mobile application market statistics to support application development endeavors. A very detailed mobile application business model is conceived according to eight key elements of an e-commerce business model. The testing of this business model will begin Fall 2018 and will be dubbed, FYI.</p>,<p>April 2, 2018</p>,<p>Ryan Roe</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://ryanroe.io/analyzing-e-commerce-business-strategies-and-developing-and-te/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5a6482e3-bb0a-401e-ad86-fb7a36a693c7</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 19:19:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Thread: Personal Development]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Thread: Personal Development</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/f5514780-a3ea-40a0-98f4-734b40792519.jpg">,<p>Photo: Weronika Gesicka</p>,<p>My blog has multiple topic threads. This is one of them.</p>,<p>The personal development thread consists of topics that pertain to building my professional career and my own online presence. I am currently working on creating an online presence for multiple clients in the Charleston area. These sites will focus on e-commerce and small businesses.</p>,<p>Posts:</p>,<ul><li><a href="http://ryanroe.io/what-is-the-grid-and-why-i-am-using-it-for-my-website" title="">AI Website Development Technology and Plans for My Personal Website</a></li></ul>,<p>Ryan Roe</p>,<p>January 1, 2018</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://ryanroe.io/personal-development/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3d21501b-e615-4763-8efa-2695ebc8a4d1</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 18:24:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[COBOL: Why a programming language built in 1959 should still be taught.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/669e4e5b-71da-46a0-9f67-524e5dfc8f75.png" title="My tn3270x COBOL emulator home screen">,<h1>COBOL: Why a programming language built in 1959 should still be taught.</h1>,<p>Thread: An Introduction to Difficult Tech Concepts</p>,<h2>Common Business Oriented Language (COBOL). What is it? What was its purpose? Who still uses it? Why do they still use it? And an interview with a software engineer hired to develop a program to convert a COBOL database to SQL.</h2>,<h3><em>“The unique capabilities of COBOL and the business reasons for them were lost in passage of time.” - Robert Glass</em></h3>,<p>February 15, 2018</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://ryanroe.io/cobol-why-a-programming-language-built-in-the-1959-is-still/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">61b9b6a0-6a92-4d1b-a901-dddf2d44f1c5</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 23:07:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Defining Big Data, Describing Big Data Analytics, and Explaining their Impact on E-Commerce]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Defining Big Data, Describing Big Data Analytics, and Explaining their Impact on E-Commerce</h1>,<h2>Thread: An Easy Intro to Difficult Tech Concepts</h2>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ec2348b5-e68e-4697-b1e5-02ab99fab844.jpg" title="NASA&apos;s &apos;Black Marble&apos; shows Earth&apos;s nighttime glow." alt="New global map of Earth at night shows the growing impact of light pollution across the globe.">,<h3>January 29, 2018</h3>,<h2>Ryan Roe</h2>]]></description>
            <link>http://ryanroe.io/defining-big-data-describing-big-data-analytics-and-explai/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4eef7df2-6cf1-4ae0-a63a-bcbb0282bcbb</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 02:55:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Artificial Website Development Technology? The Grid?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Artificial Website Development Technology? The Grid?</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/554d752c-b63e-4935-8440-8a8a7511b312.jpg">,<p>Thread: Personal Development</p>,<h2>It is great for content generation and design inspiration, but lacks in many areas.</h2>,<p>The Modern Computer Scientist must use everything at his disposal to maximize efficiency. Why I chose this platform to create my website, and my plans for migrating to another platform.</p>,<p>Ryan Roe</p>,<p>January 1, 2018</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://ryanroe.io/what-is-the-grid-and-why-i-am-using-it-for-my-website/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3e44658f-3136-4e33-85bb-c83e5859f13e</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 23:57:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Thread: Breaking Down Difficult Technology Concepts]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Thread: Breaking Down Difficult Technology Concepts</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/e3a4a4e3-68e2-4031-8954-137fac227059.jpg">,<h2>Throughout my blog you will see that each post is associated with a topic or thread. This is one of them.</h2>,<p>January 1, 2018</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://ryanroe.io/thread-breaking-down-difficult-technology-concepts/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1131c292-4132-458d-b195-3a4897bf7301</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 22:14:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Importance of Cryptocurrency on E-Commerce]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Importance of Cryptocurrency on E-Commerce</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/b5fc5638-f4bb-4a60-9375-78564d4e3bab.jpg">,<p>Thread: An Introduction to Difficult Tech Concepts</p>,<p>The invention of blockchain technology has sent the e-commerce community into a frenzy. Learn about the impact this new technology has on the modern e-commerce market.</p>,<p>8 March 2018</p>,<p>Ryan Roe</p>,<p>Artwork from <a href="https://werk-schau.blogspot.com/2013/08/will-art-for-cash.html?showComment=1523334635238#c8984958777946706246" title="Peter Frölich's Blog">Peter Frölich</a></p>]]></description>
            <link>http://ryanroe.io/the-importance-of-cryptocurrency-on-e-commerce/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">f8c94e69-9c74-4e5e-a6d3-b4f5b0ee42db</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 04:46:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[About Me]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>About Me</h1>,<p>Please see the “Hire Me” page for professional competencies.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/e84858ba-0c7d-4880-9614-2eb636a3a3ea.jpg">,<p>I am a Charleston native and intend to live there for the rest of my life.</p>,<p>I am a recent graduate from The University of South Carolina (USC) which developed my skills and experiences in two seemingly opposite directions.</p>,<p>The first area of growth is relationally as a manager of large scale social projects. I chartered a Social Philanthropy fraternity, Theta Chi, as a freshman with only 30 other people. Over the years I have taken the lead in almost every project whether it be social, organizational, institutional, philanthropic, or political as Vice President. The organization now maintains over 120 members. The connections and experience I gained awarded me an interview with the previous Student Body President, Ross Lordo, for a position on his cabinet as Director of Cockstock. Cockstock is USC’s name for a free homecoming concert built using a $100,000 conglomeration of 5 different student organization’s budgets. I was tasked with overseeing budget spending and coordinating these organizations, each consisting of their own bureaucracy to create successful event. Planning a concert of this size is not difficult: quote multiple venues, talent agencies, production companies, and security companies, poll the students, set up ticket sales, hire graphic designers, and then market through the appropriate channels. I utilized posters, stickers, tabling, talked alone in front of sorority meetings (200+ people), and utilized social media, particularly my friend’s account, Drinking Ticket. The difficult piece of Cockstock was politically extracting $100,000 from a state funded public university’s representatives as an undergraduate student. The Cockstock program is only in its second year, and this project required over 8 months of my time constantly meeting, calling, and coordinating. An unsuccessful event, high cost per head, would result in the cancellation of the budget allotment and the end of the program. The venue sold out at 10,000 people and I successfully planned the largest student run event at The University of South Carolina to date.</p>,<p>The second area of growth is technically as a student of Computer Science. Degrees in Computer Science teach students very little in the current academic climate and most knowledge is self-taught. The value in the degree comes with a general overview of the available technologies, a few projects, and the community I was introduced to. I have designed programs in Java, C++, TypeScript/CSS/HTML. I have built relational databased using SQL and constructed COBOL databases on IBM mainframes through a ISPF Unix Distribution, tn 3270x. I have garnered a tremendous interest in Linux and Hybrid Mobile Application Development technology. I am currently developing a mobile application, Beacon and contracting a revolutionary technology in the form of a hybrid mobile app dubbed FYI. I also have a fascination with many aspects of technology as you can see. This website is my technology project that grows along with me. The blog posts will focus on the history of technology, hybrid mobile application technology, the current climate of monetizing mobile applications, and breaking down complex technical subjects for easy introduction, specifically cryptocurrency, e-commerce, reprogrammable computing, Big Data (one of my favorites), and much more.</p>,<p>With Love - Ryan Roe</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://ryanroe.io/about-me/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7cce628b-8444-4504-8768-8fa6f2dd6c33</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 04:00:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>